Zayne Lockhart

ZayneLockhartVO@gmail.com

(205) 275-5613

Skills

SQL: MySQL, Miscrosoft SQL Server.

Years of Experience: 1

I have used SQL for data cleaning, data verification, and manipulating large data sets via joins, temporary tables, calculations, and subqueries.

Microsoft Excel:

Years of Experience: 3

I have used Excel to clean data, manipulate small sets of data, create basic visualizations, utilize formulae and functions, and create pivot tables.

Python:

Years of Experience: 4

Python, Pandas, Matplotlib, NumPy. I have used Python and the previously mentioned libraries to create visualizations of data tables created in Excel, manipulate and analyze data, and for data cleaning.

Tableau, PowerBI:

Years of Experience: 1

I have used these programs to create robust visualizations and dashboards for data sets that I have cleaned and analyzed using the above methods.

R:

Years of Experience: 1

I learned R and the tidyverse suite of packages through the Google Data Analytics program. In said program, I used R to clean data, manipulate and transform data, visualize data, and create markdown sheets to present my findings.

Portfolio

ZiggyZayne.GitHub.io

This is the link to my portfolio page which features the projects listed below as well as links to my contact info, GitHub, and LinkedIn. I built the page using HTML and CSS and will continue updating as I complete more analyses!

Projects

Mushroom Distribution in Alabama: This project is still in progress and is the largest I have

worked on. I have taken mushroom distribution data from INaturalist for several species of mushroom, cleaned said data using Excel, then filtered the entries by their location accuracy (within 5km) in SQL, and imported the data to Tableau and mapped out the coordinates on a map of Alabama.

Employee Salaries Project: For this project I used a dataset provided by Kaggle. I cleaned, verified, and analyzed the data in Python, then used the Matplotlib and pandas libraries to glean and visualize the salary distribution data analysts across various levels of expertise and across different sized companies.

Certifications

Google Data Analytics Certification: Covered Excel, Tableau, SQL, and R, as well as best practices and the data analysis life cycle and process. Completed January 2024.

Education

Walker High School: Graduated May 2013.

The University of Alabama: 2015-2020. Bachelor's of Music - Vocal Performance.

Incomplete.

Northwest Shoals Community College: 2023. EMT Basic.

Work History

Dynamic Security/United Launch Alliance Fire/EMT

July 2023 - Present

In this position I am responsible for inspecting, testing, and maintaining fire protection systems, responding to medical emergencies, as well as various office administrative duties including creating spreadsheets for inventory.

Lifeguard Ambulance Service

EMT Basic

June 2023 - November 2023

In this position I was responsible for responding to 911 medical emergencies, documenting the events and interventions in great detail, and public outreach/relations for Lauderdale County EMS.

Printers and Stationers Inc.
Copier Tech/IT

Oopier reciniti

January 2023 - May 2023

In this position I was responsible for diagnosing and fixing issues related to copiers, both in their mechanical operation and related to their connection to the network. The calls I was sent to most often were of the IT nature including network connectivity issues, print driver installations, initial setup of copiers on the network, and keeping track of work performed for customers in a spreadsheet.

North Wood Social Bar Manager

October 2021 - October 2022

In this position I was responsible for daily opening and closing duties including cleaning, counting down the drawer, and ingredient preparation for cocktails, bar service, menu crafting, beer and wine selection, and inventory upkeep.